Hadi Sinaee

+1 (604)-347-8559 | sinaee.hadi@gmail.com | linkedin | github | Canada

SUMMARY

I am a **software engineer** with more than **5 years** of experience in building **distributed systems** and **infrastructures** designed to perform in **concurrent** scenarios. I have delivered **highly scalable and performant** solutions for businesses with **millions of users**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant - Systems Software Engineer

Systopia Lab, University of British Columbia

Jan 2021 - Oct 2023

- Devised a graph partitioner using C++ that achieved 70% higher quality partitioning than the state-of-the-art.
- Implemented parallel graph partitioning features with **OpenMP**, achieving a **50**% reduction in execution time.
- Extended a multithreaded Python FaaS profiler to support Knative along with OpenWhisk.

Senior Software Engineering Consultant - Remote

Torob Inc., Search Engine for Online Shopping

Apr 2020 - Dec 2020

- Mentored Senior Software Engineers and Product Managers for a product serving 9M+ users.
- Engineered data analysis using **SQL**, **Python** and **Pandas**, optimizing the shop's ranking system by %10.
- Transitioned 100% of product development and management to the GitLab platform.

Staff Software Engineer

Ostadkar, A Marketplace for Home Services

Mar 2019 - Feb 2020

- Led cross-functional teams (+30) in engineering and data analytic for a 1M+ user marketplace.
- *Achieved deployment of* **10**+ microservices to the **Kubernetes** cluster with an event-driven architecture, resulting in a **50**% increase in availability and a **75**% reduction in tail latency.
- *Implemented* **CI/CD** pipelines with GitLab and streamlined Docker packaging, achieving a **50**% reduction in deployment time.

Senior Software Engineer

Ostadkar, A Marketplace for Home Services

Jul 2018 - Mar 2019

- *Designed and implemented a new microservice* using an event-driven architecture, expanding the company's offerings in a new line of business.
- Optimized API throughput by **doubling** performance through effective caching and query optimization.
- *Contributed* to hiring three Sr. Software Engineers and actively participated in the optimization of the hiring process.

Software Engineer - Co-Founder

HodHod IM, Instant Messaging Application

Jul 2015 – Jul 2018

- Attained 200K+ DAU and 2M+ installs with +1M users.
- Designed a distributed messaging architecture using an event-driven approach, resulting in a yearly revenue generation of over 10B IRR.

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Systems, supervised by Prof. Margo Seltzer

Jan 2021 – Oct 2023

Sharif University of Technology¹

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Machine Learning

Sep 2013 – Feb 2016

SKILLS

Languages: Go / Golang, C, C++, Python

Technologies: Docker, Kubernetes, Knative, Kafka, Redis, MongoDB, Django, Flask, Terraform

Misc.: Git, CI/CD, OpenMP, Nginx, gRPC, AWS, Networking, Virtualization

¹It is considered as the nation's most prestigious and leading institution for STEM fields.